A Guide to the Papers of Elsie Fowke Jackson, 1664-1968
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Elsie Fowke Jackson 1664-1968
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6589-k
This collection consists of ca. 40 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This accession was given to the Library by Elsie Fowkes Jackson, of Alexandria, Virginia, on March 11, 1980.
Scope and Content Information
This accession consists of ca. 40 items, 1664-1968, letters, legal documents and notes, photographs, Confederate money, and newspaper and magazine clippings regarding various historical figures and events. Most of the items, some of which are photostatic or electrostatic copies of the originals, relate to the Fowke or Reed families of Maryland and Virginia. In addition, there are letters regarding the genealogy of the Fowke and Mason families, as well as magazine clippings and photographs regarding historical figures and events. Included is a legal document signed by William Berkeley, governor of Virginia, concerning land owned by Gerard Fowkes in Westmoreland County, Virginia.
Arrangement
The genealogical material, material regarding historical figures and events, and memorabilia have been placed at the end of the collection. All other items are in chronological order.
Contents List
- Miscellaneous documents and notes re a dispute over land owned by the Fowke family 1664, n.d.
- Land Patent of Gerard Fowke 1666 Feb 15
- Document of Fairfax County Court re claims for property "impressed or taken for public service" (photostatic copy) 1782 Feb
- John Reed to Joseph [Reed] (photographic copy) 1861 May 2, ALS
- Newspaper clipping, receipt, and checks re Reed family 1864-1872, 1934
- Music manuscript from Susan Fowke's harpsichord music lesson book 1870 Jan 10
- H. M. Proctor, H. B. Proctor, John A. Bayly, William Cox, Henry Bauer, and John Willey to Capt. Fowkes 1870 July 25, ALS
- Resolutions adopted by Harmony Lodge, No. 21 K of P, Washington, D. C., on the death of William Fowke 1873 Apr 3
- [?] to Leutenant Thomas Jenkins re military orders for his company to meet 1813 Apr 11, ALS
- Inventory of household items n.d.
- Letters re Fowke and Mason family genealogy 1886, 1890, 1968
- Photographs and newspaper clippings re historical figures and events n.d.
- Memorabilia n.d.
- Land deed for "Mathapungo" to Anne Fowke (Photographic copy) 1674 May 20
- Family name index of deeds, deeds of trusts, release deeds and wills, King George County, Virginia: Fowke family (photographic copies) n.d.